# **Dzenan Culesker**

https://dzenan-culesker-portfolio.vercel.app/dzenanculesker@gmail.com 4074373964

Atlanta, GA, USA

# **Objective**

Software Developer, and Engineer having over 2 years of experience of bringing products from concept to final product in the engineering field. Aiming to learn, grow, and apply my skills to ensure a successful career in front-end software development with an emphasis in designing new programs/applications that are simple to use. Specializations include UI/UX design, and product development.

### **Projects**

### Pokemon Search App (August 2024 - October 2024)

- Designed layout (HTML5, CSS3 & Framer Motion) of the search app user interface in the shape of the original Pokedex design
- Constructed functional components (React, Next.js & TypeScript) to use user input on user interface to display the sprite and information of searched Pokemon
- Accessed information of searched Pokemon using the Pokemon API (React, Next.js & TypeScript)
- Developed app responsivity to accommodate different-sized screens (especially Mobile)

### Random Quote Machine (February 2024 - March 2024)

- Generated layout of the UI (HTML5, CSS3, & Bootstrap)
- Fetched quotes from a web API to acquire quotes (React & JavaScript)
- Ability to randomize which quote is selected from API and tweet said quote (React & JavaScript)

## **Work Experience**

#### Starrett Bytewise, Columbus GA - Sensor Design Engineer (September 2022 - August 2023)

- Design, and model (Inventor) opto-mechanical and optical aspects of new sensor projects
- Lead building, calibrating, and troubleshooting of current and new sensors
- Use rapid prototyping (3d printing) to reduce cost and time for results in sensor testing
- Develop technical assembly documents (Word) for sensors

#### Mitsubishi Power, Orlando FL - Mechanical Engineering Associate (January 2020 - May 2021)

- Designed, modeled (Solidworks), planned, and tested plugs for shot peening of turbine blades
- Measured, designed, modeled (Solidworks), and built rack for control box of CMM machine using leftover parts
- Edited and managed work instructions (SOPs) used in turbine blade and vane production
- Used Action Plans, Time Charts, and Gantt Charts to keep track of project progress

### Certifications

- Responsive Web Design (FreeCodeCamp)
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (FreeCodeCamp)
- Front End Development Libraries (FreeCodeCamp)

### **Education**

University of Central Florida, Orlando FL - Mechanical Engineering B.S. GPA: 3.721 (August 2017 - May 2021)